{
	"Overall": [
		{"question":"did you like it",
		"answer":"yeah it was fine"},
		{"question":"was it good",
		"answer":"yeah it was fine"},
		{"question":"would you recommend it to someone",
		"answer":"yeah especially if they like dnd"},
		{"question":"what did you think it was going to be before you played it?",
		"answer":"i thought maybe like oregon trail or civilization 3 i wasnt sure honestly. didnt have too good of an idea."},
		{"question":"wha did you think it was going to be like at the title screen?",
		"answer":"same, oregon trail or civ 3"},
		{"question":"what did you think 15 min in?",
		"answer":"oh s*** i gotta go fast there is no slowing down. should i be exploring and taking risks? okay im gonna give it a shot"},
		{"question":"what did you think 1 hour in?",
		"answer":"this is pretty fun i am enjoying making plans and traveling"},
		{"question":"what did you think in the middle?",
		"answer":"f*** f*** F*** gotta go fast i did Not enjoy getting ripped into south africa from like, iraq. i had india mapped out! i wanted to see india! it sucked! and then i got kidnapped by nemo! i wanted to see china! and korea! it was like the most inconvenient path mannnn"},
		{"question":"what did you think at 3/4?",
		"answer":"shit man ive been DrAgGEd around the eastern hemisphere im exhausted and salty that i got thrown back and all the way to south africa and kidnapped and then there was the stupid mutiny that didnt work and seemed like..just a reason to piss people off?"},
		{"question":"what did you think at the end?",
		"answer":"you know what, that was pretty good but i need a break before i do that again"},
		{"question":"did you actually finish?",
		"answer":"yeah took me 91 days lol so technically i finished a whole round"}
	],
	"Art": {
		"Graphics": [
			{"question":"what does it look like?",
			"answer":"blocky graphics, silhouettes or however you spell that. basic shapes, 2d"},
			{"question":"what is the visual style",
			"answer":"sparse, cartoon style, mostly black with color block"},
			{"question":"tone",
			"answer":"colorful, bright, flat, very 2d. like a jules verne novel, honestly. fantastical but still grounded in the reality of the era"},
			{"question":"what is the composition of the UI",
			"answer":"'blocky, text heavy in the middle, big central graphic, transportation on the left hand side, ''phogg -approval meter'' on the right side. small icons at the bottom and top of hte screen for navigation'"},
			{"question":"what do the menu screens look like?",
			"answer":"menu screen is modal pop-up, very sparse and plain"},
			{"question":"what is the color pallete",
			"answer":"bright colors, mostly dark and matte colors with pops of color"},
			{"question":"what is the animation style",
			"answer":"no actual animation, just cartoon style static graphics and moving text prompts"},
			{"question":"2d or 3d?",
			"answer":"2d"},
			{"question":"cookie cutter or unique?",
			"answer":"'a mix. it definitely wasn't built off a template, but the concept is simple enough that i wouldnt call it ''unique'''"},
			{"question":"what are the diegetic visuals like?",
			"answer":"as realistic as possible. a world in turmoil but blasting full speed ahead"},
			{"question":"what are the non-diegetic visuals like?",
			"answer":"bright and blocky as i said"}
		],
		"Sound": [
			{"question":"does the audio add to the immersion?",
			"answer":"its artificial, basic sound stuff. crowds chattering in cities, crickets at night time, different locations had different special additions, like in south africa there were drums, etc. vague musical genre/style differences. the sound effects for each mode of transportation are cute."},
			{"question":"are there any recurring musical motifs?",
			"answer":"not really theres just background music while youre looking at other stuff"},
			{"question":"genre of music",
			"answer":"N/A"},
			{"question":"tone? ",
			"answer":"N/A the sound in this is basically a formality"},
			{"question":"sound effects",
			"answer":"as i mentioned, crowds, crickets, steam roaring,"},
			{"question":"instrumentation?",
			"answer":"changed depending on location"}
		],
		"Story": [
			{"question":"what is the story? ",
			"answer":"the basic premise is around the world in 80 days. fileas phogg makes a bet with the royal society that he can make it around the world in 80 days. so you are his valet and you gotta take him around the world and manage inventory and money and his mood. and you have to explore to discover routes. if you don't make it in 80 days, you try to get back as fast as you can so you can go around again. so i guess thats a positive message?"},
			{"question":"who are the characters?",
			"answer":"phileas phogg, jean passeportou something french like that. and then all the people we meet around the world"},
			{"question":"what genre of story is it? ",
			"answer":"science fiction steampunk"},
			{"question":"what are the main plot points? ",
			"answer":"we leave london, we try to make it back to london lol. in my playthrough specifically, we left london, went east across europe down italy to greece to like turkey ish to alexandria to cairo to ottoman empire but while i was in the middle of the desert i got KIDNAPPED AND TELEPORTED to south africa which honestly sucked. if im being honest, that was a wrench in my plans. i learned that your plans can get upset at any moment. while i was crossing the indian ocean i got kidnapped AGAIN by captain nemo which was kinda cool but still annoying. by the time we escaped we made it to indonesia and manila to japan. then we went to go to san francisco but we got caught in a storm so we got re-routed to honolulu and phogg told me to organize a mutiny?? so i tried to do that but i failed. id pretty much failed the game by this point, since i left japan on day 60 and by the time i got to san francisco it was day 80. but anyway i failed at the random mutiny request and kept going on to honolulu. then i tried to go to san francisco. id been trading pretty well so i had a lot of money and i basically spent the rest of the game across the us talking to people. finally i left new york and the airship supposedly was the fastest? i couldnt figure out if it was fastest to go to the island in the middle of the atlantic via washington, or from new york to london. couldnt tell honestly. anyway i got back and phogg said the only way to redeem ourselves is try again"},
			{"question":"do they feel natural to the game?",
			"answer":"yeah i mean thats kinda the entire point of hte game is the story so actually yes it does"},
			{"question":"is there a lot of exposition",
			"answer":"no but also not much is necessary"},
			{"question":"what are the stakes",
			"answer":"the pressure of possibly failing, trying to get the most options by talking to people"},
			{"question":"who is the main character?",
			"answer":"passeportou, the valet of phileas"},
			{"question":"who is a standout side character",
			"answer":"phileas phogg lol"},
			{"question":"what is the setting",
			"answer":"steampunk world. the major cities of the world in the late 1860s. they mention lots of historical events for context, while also putting some fictional elements that are steampunk"},
			{"question":"what are the emotional climaxes",
			"answer":"its basically just the ever present pressure of failure which to be honest detracted from the fun."},
			{"question":"what is the structure of the plot?",
			"answer":"its the overarching plot of circumnavigation, with sidequests possible in most cities"},
			{"question":"any big reveals?",
			"answer":"i mean not really, depending on what you run into youll get into different things. like i guess it was a big reveal that captain nemo existed but i wasn't emotionally impacted. it just added to the story."},
			{"question":"any notable foreshadowing?",
			"answer":"since most of it is procedurally generated or randomly generated or both, there isnt really a point in foreshadowing"}
		],
		"Themes": [
			{"question":"what is the message of the game?",
			"answer":"keeping an open mind, traveling and appreciating the differences in diversity etc"},
			{"question":"what is the game trying to convey?",
			"answer":"tolerance and adventurousness"},
			{"question":"is it successful? ",
			"answer":"yeah id say so"},
			{"question":"what are the major themes?",
			"answer":"war, the aftermath of war mostly, racial and religious tension but mostly the generally goodness of humans, tolerance, courage, riskiness. seems like they want you to be flexible and take risks"},
			{"question":"what tropes are used? ",
			"answer":"'the atrocities of slavery and different types of racism, sexism is a strong theme for the first half. mental health. theres a gay subplot so that was something. imperialism was a doozy. revolutionaries.america as simple farmers, very east vs west ''europe vs everyone else''. mystical stuff in the east in the ''orient'' and africa, all very secretive and amazing to his european eyes. and then america is simple. no homophobia that i saw, so thats interesting. also being english and french ''gentlemen'' helped us a lot in america and imperialized nations. which we used to our benefit. and i dont love that but its ''realistic'' i guess.'"},
			{"question":"what are some symbols?",
			"answer":"'a lot of the methods of transportation are related to labor and the working class, urbanization, humans being replaced by machines, etc. also in the ''orient'' women are treated equally to men which you can optionally be offended by, which..is something. But if you are sexist you do get in trouble and you lose respect from phogg. so in that sense its nice. '"},
			{"question":"objects of significance?",
			"answer":"merchant goods and technology can be traded at markets in each city during the day. you manage your budget and you can invest in items to sell later. some transportation can be tricky though and restrict your ability to carry stuff"},
			{"question":"relationships between characters",
			"answer":"'phileas is my ''master'' because im a valet. which was a weird but persistent vibe. our character had a variety of options for speech but generally was content and proud of his profession. i take that as an endorsement for the system but thats my opinion.'"},
			{"question":"who are friends?",
			"answer":"various side quest characters are introduced. they are friends or comrades or siblings etc"},
			{"question":"who are the COC?",
			"answer":"'owing to the globalization of the time, the cities have a pretty consistent mix of diverse races. in asia and africa and i assume south america this is obviously amplified. i dont love that everywhere we go we're mostly regard with respect and wonder, and are able to ''british'' our way out of most problems. so that kind of defeats the purpose of the diversity. and we get ''woke points'' for not being as conservative as the people of the time might have been.'"},
			{"question":"who are the LGBTQC?",
			"answer":"'i actually ran into a few explicitly gay characters throughout america. so i slept with a black man in post civil war new orleans, so thats cool. but also he was hypersexualized and ''mystical'' for mardi gras so that was less than ideal.'"},
			{"question":"any allusions/references?",
			"answer":"'references to jules verne works, 20000 leagues under the sea, generic ''lost city in the desert'', generic ''sea monster'', generic ''anti imperialist revolutionary'',  more of the like. steam punk elements.'"}
		]
	},
	"Gameplay": {
		"Mechanics": [
			{"question":"how does the game work? ",
			"answer":"click on dialogue/action elements on screen and read responses and prompts"},
			{"question":"is it fun to play?",
			"answer":"yeah the side quests are fun and interesting"},
			{"question":"is it interesting to play?",
			"answer":"yes"},
			{"question":"how do you progress?",
			"answer":"asking questions and exploring to find new routes, talking to other travellers to learn about other locations"},
			{"question":"win?",
			"answer":"go around the world in less than 81 days hahaha pretty straight forward"},
			{"question":"what are the controls",
			"answer":"click with the mouse"},
			{"question":"did you play it on the controller",
			"answer":"yes with mousepad right pad"},
			{"question":"is there customization?",
			"answer":"i didnt check it didnt seem necessary"},
			{"question":"is pausing encouraged?",
			"answer":"there is no pause that i could find. but then, i didnt really try to pause. i was very engaged. they are very clear that EVERY action takes time. consulting the map takes time. you cant get Any time back. i guess i could have tried immediately quitting, but i missed a train by Seconds which was very frustrating.anyway it all contributes to a rushed pace while also encouraging exploration because risks can get you somewhere faster"},
			{"question":"is any particular playing style encouraged?",
			"answer":"yeah they want you to play fast and loose. bet big, win big. try out however you can so you can try to find a faster way. you can negotiate with some transportation to leave earlier than planned, sometimes much earlier. they aren't afraid to throw you halfway across the world for at the drop of a hat. they want you on your toes to add authenticity to the experience. it was pretty effective honestly, and fun. always trying to make the best of what i had with all the interruptions and disasters and lucky breaks. i was engaged. it was also nice to always have the finish line in sight."}
		],
		"Difficulty": [
			{"question":"what is the pacing of the game?",
			"answer":"a lot of quick moves across europe and asia, across the oceans and across the us it slows down while youre stuck with the same characters for a while"},
			{"question":"what is the difficulty curve?",
			"answer":"consistent the whole way. they use randomness to keep the challenge up, i think"},
			{"question":"is it too hard?",
			"answer":"'nah, i think it was really good, actually. there was plenty of buffer with money, and Lots of buffer with my ''approval meter'' i barely ever dipped below 50 and wasn't really trying. things got pretty bad and he was never that mad. i didn't make it in 80 days in the first attempt but i never felt like i was stuck, and i feel encouraged to try again with everything i know about the world to try and make it faster.'"},
			{"question":"is the tutorial sufficient? ",
			"answer":"'yeah it was easy. it was basically just packing for the trip before we left for the first city, which i think is always paris in the first go. we rush to get on the train, and if you lie to the guard and say you lost your ticket when you know you didnt buy one, phileas is disappointed with you and then just solves the problem with money, which is a pretty obvious message to try using money to solve your problems instead of subterfuge. okay, but then later when we were crossing the pacific he was like ''you have to mutiny NOW'' which is a pretty stark contradiction but whatever. he wasn't even that mad that i failed so the stakes in retrospect were pretty low anyway.'"},
			{"question":"does the difficulty match the context of the game?",
			"answer":"yeah i think so. you get better as you learn more about the world which is what they want you to do"},
			{"question":"when did the game hit a slump",
			"answer":"across the oceans. i liked the faster pace of the close cities with lots of different experiences instead of a bunch of dialogue stuff. but i mean maybe i wouldve been burnt out if i was constantly dashing around. i also kinda suspect that dashing around will lead to the fastest path."},
			{"question":"how often did you feel frustrated",
			"answer":"when i was thwarted in what i was planning, whether thats something i wanted to trade or a city i wanted to get to that i missed (or was ripped away from)"},
			{"question":"how often did you feel triumphant",
			"answer":"when i got lucky or one of my plans paid off. it felt So good to sell the object i carried for hundreds of miles knowing id get a huge payoff for it. and phogg would compliment you too. so it was a nice reward for being patient and thinking ahead within the context of the travel"},
			{"question":"did you feel like you had to force yourself to start/keep playing",
			"answer":"nope i was all in. but i also knew it was gonna be over soon"},
			{"question":"is there an explicit tutorial?",
			"answer":"no"},
			{"question":"is there a subtle tutorial?",
			"answer":"yep i explained it above"},
			{"question":"what parts felt unfairly hard?",
			"answer":"'nothing felt ''unfair'' but it did suck to get teleported across the entirety of africa when i already had a plan to go through india'"},
			{"question":"what parts felt too easy?",
			"answer":"'the prices were pretty buffered so i was never in need of funds, and phogg was pretty happy the whole time so i was never in danger of dipping below 0 and getting ''fired'' or whatever the consequence wouldve been'"}
		],
		"Experience": [
			{"question":"smooth playing experience? ",
			"answer":"yep very basic and smooth"},
			{"question":"any glitches  that detracted from the game?",
			"answer":"nope mechanics were chill no complaints"},
			{"question":"inconveneint areas?",
			"answer":"it was kinda hard to navigate and click on the city so i could go, especially when the path was super long. i missed a few days cutting the time too close and missing the transport since i couldnt click on the tiny city across the map in time. that taught me to not cut it close with time, but still it wasn't pleasant and it couldve been easier to let me click anywhere on the path."},
			{"question":"here is the place that the criticism usually goes",
			"answer":"see above. also yeah some of the imperialism vibes werent awesome. they tried to address it with progressive mindset and thats good but i feel like it wasn't as much as it couldve done. that said, i clearly have only experienced a fraction of the game. i think itll be interesting to see how a second playthrough goes"},
			{"question":"did you ever feel sincerely irritated at the game",
			"answer":"when i got teleported, but i got over it real quick because time didnt stop ticking"},
			{"question":"what did you want that you didnt get",
			"answer":"idk, i dont think its that deep"},
			{"question":"what did you not expect that you really enjoyed",
			"answer":"the stories were pretty fun. i really did enjoy taking risks and getting rewarded when they paid off. it made the losses feel worth it"},
			{"question":"what made you stop and appreciate the game",
			"answer":"the creativity of the stories were fun. i felt like it was a really cool depiction of what playing DnD would be. a real RPG with a lot of replayability. i appreciated that design thats a cool framework for a game"},
			{"question":"did you have to take a break because it was too good",
			"answer":"no haha lol"}
		]
	},
	"pull":"SET_QUOTE",
	"game":{"title":"80 Days"},
	"author":{"name":"holden"},
	"slug":"80_days",
	"imgs":["","",""]
}